<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<component type="desktop">

	<id>com.github.limads.Queries.desktop</id>
	
	<metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
	
	<project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
	
	<summary>A workbench to interact with relational databases.</summary>
	
	<description>
	  <p>Queries is a workbench to interact with relational databases, with initial support for the Postgres
	  database management system (DBMS).</p>
	  
	  <p>Features</p>
	  
	  <ul>
	  <li>Feel at home: Establishing a database connection immediately shows all the relevant
	  database contextual information (schemata, tables, views and columns) that
	  you need to write valid SQL.</li>
	  <li>Correctness: All SQL is parsed and verified at the client side before being
	  sent to the database server, allowing immediate feedback and faster iteration cycles when writing
	  and debugging complex queries.</li>
	  <li>Security: Queries supports encrypted connections via SSL and TLS,
	  allowing you to interact safely with remote (cloud or on-premise) databases.</li>
	  <li>Performance: Queries examines written statement sequences and executes them asynchronously 
	  when possible. That means that a script total execution time is bounded by the slowest query,
	  and not by the ammount of statements you send to the server at the same time.</li>
	  <li>Data visualization and reporting: Build line, scatter and bar graphs without external tools
	  using plain SQL, simply by aggregating your data according to a valid JSON specification.
	  Export tables as plain CSV files and build dynamic HTML reports containing rich </li>
	  </ul>
	
	</description>
	
	<categories>
        <category>Office</category>
        <category>Development</category>
    </categories>
    
    <keywords>
      <keyword translate="no">SQL</keyword>
      <keyword translate="no">DBMS</keyword>
      <keyword translate="no">Database</keyword>
      <keyword translate="no">Postgres</keyword>
      <keyword translate="no">Data</keyword>
  </keywords>
  
    <icon>
    </icon>
    
	<developer_name>Diego Lima</developer_name>
	
    <url type="homepage">https://github.com/limads/queries</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/limads/queries/issues</url>
    <url type="donation">https://www.gnome.org/donate/</url>
    <url type="help">https://github.com/limads/queries</url>
    
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://github.com/limads/queries/blob/master/data/icons/hicolor/128x128/apps/com.github.limads.Queries.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  
  <releases>
    <release version="0.1" date="2022-10-07">
     <description>
        <p> Initial release</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  
</component>
